(綱手)うん 問題ない。
Okay. No problems.
よし！ 今日で退院だ。
All right, you can leave
the hospital today.
(カカシ)ひょっとして
そこのお荷物を➡
By any chance,
this isn't because
you want me to hurry up
早く持って行って
ほしいからじゃないですよね？
and take that baggage
with me, is it?
(ナルト)ガーッ…。
まぁ それもあるがな。
Well, there's that, too...
(サクラ)ナルトったら いつでも
修業が始められるようにって➡
That Naruto.
He refuses to leave
the hospital room
病室から離れなくって…。
so he can be ready to start training
at any moment...
ホントは 数日自宅でゴロゴロ… いえ
療養してからと思ってましたが➡
Truthfully, I was going to start
after kicking back.
I mean, recuperating
at home for a few days.
読む本も
なくなってしまいましたし…。
But I've run out of books to read...
チャッチャと修業やってしまいますか。
So I guess I'll just get right
to the training.
うん そうだな。
螺旋！
That's right...
Rasen!
ムニャムニャ…。
やった～ オイラの勝ち…。
All right! I win.
You have to treat me to
a year's worth of Ichiraku Ramen.
起きろ バカナルト！
Wake up, Idiot Naruto!
ブサイク… ん？
Ugly...
- Huh?!
- Huh?
しゃ～んなろ～！
サクラちゃん！
Shannaro!
Sakura-chan...
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
I haven't learned "sadness" yet.
kanashimi wa mada oboerarezu
And I'm just starting to grasp "misery".
setsunasa wa ima tsukami hajimeta
Even this feeling I hold towards you.
anata e to idaku kono kanjou mo
Is now turning into "words".
ima kotoba ni wakatteku
Waking up from the dream of this unknown world.
michi naru sekai no yume kara mezamete
I spread these wings and fly.
kono hane wo hiroge tobi datsu
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Knowing I'll find the answer,
tsuki nuketara
If I pierce through it.
mitsukaru to shitte
if I break free,
furikiru hodo
From that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Wind
さて 修業だ。
エヘヘヘッ…。
Okay, time for some training.
何だ？
What is it?
いやさ なんか
カカシ先生との修業って久しぶりで➡
Well, it's been a long time
since I've trained with you...
何でか よくわかんねんだけど
嬉しいんだってばよ！
I don't really know why,
but I'm glad...
I see.
そうか。
エヘヘヘッ…。
(カカシ)アハハハッ…
笑ってられんのも今のうちだぞ。
Laugh it up while you can.
えっ？
時間は待っちゃくれないからな。
Time won't wait for us, so...
As I told you at the hospital,
病院でも言ったが
今回の修業の目的は➡
the purpose of this training is
to create a Ninjutsu
お前だけの
最強忍術をつくることにある。
of ultimate power just for you.
螺旋丸を超える術だ。
A Jutsu that will exceed
the Rasengan.
それには チャクラの性質変化と➡
Two techniques,
"Change in Chakra Nature"
and "Change in Chakra Form"
are crucial for that...
形態変化の
２つのテクニックが不可欠だ。
形態変化と 性質の変化？
Change in Chakra Form
and Change in... Chakra Nature?
ん？ ハイハイ。
一度に２つはわかんないね。
Okay, okay. You can't understand
two things at once.
I was wrong.
Sorry about that.
先生 悪かった ごめんごめん。
いや～ アハハハッ…。
Then, first let's go with the explanation
of Change in Chakra Form.
じゃあ まずは
形態変化の説明からいこう。
オッス！
(カカシ)螺旋丸をつくってみろ。
Right!
Try making a Rasengan.
Huh?
あっ？ いいってばよ！
Sure.
Let's go!
いくぜ！
おう！
Right!
螺旋丸！
Rasengan!
Okay, stop!
はい ストップ！
えっ？
You've already mastered
the Change in Chakra Form.
お前はもう チャクラの
形態変化は マスターしている。
えっ？
その螺旋丸がそうだ。
Your Rasengan has done that.
R-Rasengan...
螺旋丸…。
Spinning Chakra like mad at
a super-high speed
チャクラを
超スピードで乱回転させて 圧縮する。
and then compressing it...
このこと自体が
チャクラの形態変化であり➡
This in itself is
the Change in Chakra Form
and the Rasengan is a Jutsu
that has carried that to the extreme.
螺旋丸は それを極めた術だ。
Then that means I've passed
the Change in Chakra Form?
じゃあ 形態変化は合格ってこと？
Yeah, that's about the size of it.
そういうこと。
アハハハッ… ヤッホイ！
Yahoo!
はい 次はチャクラの性質変化だ。
Okay, next is
the Change in Chakra Nature.
Right, right...
うん うん！
Let's see...
Take Chidori for example...
そうだな 例えば千鳥。
This is a Jutsu activated
by simultaneously creating
この術は チャクラの形態変化と➡
性質変化 ２つの変化を同時に
起こして発動させる術だが…。
both the Change in Chakra Nature
and Change in Chakra Form...
見てろ。
右手にチャクラを集中させる…。
Watch this. I concentrate
Chakra in my right hand...
I shift the property of this Chakra
into electrical current.
このチャクラを電流に性質変化させる。
So this is the Change in Chakra Nature...
これが 性質変化？
That's right.
そうだ。 そして 今度は
放電するよう形態変化させて➡
And now I shift the form
so it will discharge electricity
and then I determine the range
and strength of the attack.
攻撃の威力と範囲を決める。
In order to learn a Jutsu above
that of the Rasengan,
今までの螺旋丸以上の術を
習得するには 千鳥のように➡
this combination of
the Change in Chakra Form
形態変化と性質変化
この２つの組み合わせが➡
and Change in Chakra Nature
絶対に必要となってくるわけだ。
is absolutely necessary,
like with the Chidori.
ヘヘヘ… じゃあ オレも 螺旋丸に
その性質変化ってのを加えたら➡
Then I'll be able to complete
a new Jutsu in a flash
if I add that Change in Chakra Nature
to my Rasengan!
あっという間に
新術完成しちまうってばよ！
ダハッ…。
Listen.
That's easier said than done.
あのね 簡単に言ってくれるなよ。
第一 まだ お前は 性質変化を
習得してもいないんだからね。
In the first place, you still haven't
even learned Change in Chakra Nature.
それに お前 自分が➡
And you don't even know
what Chakra Property you have, right?
どの性質を持っているかも
知らないだろう？
Huh?! What Chakra Property?
どの性質って？
ハァ… まぁ そこから
説明しなけりゃとは思ってたけど。
Well, I figured I'd have to start
explaining from there...
いいか？ 基本的に
チャクラの性質変化の種別は➡
Listen up.
Basically there are only five types
of Chakra Properties.
５種類しかない。 火 風 水
雷 土の５種類だ。
The five types are fire, wind,
water, lightning and earth.
Fire
Wind
Water
Lightning
Earth
そもそも この基本性質は
忍び五大国の名の由来でもあり➡
These basic properties are the basis
for the names of
the "Five Great Nations"
and they're also the foundations
of all Ninjutsu.
すべての忍術の基礎だ。
No kidding. Really...?
ふ～ん… そうだったのか。
Everyone generally has Chakra
that falls under one of these properties.
だいたい みな どれかの性質に
当てはまるチャクラを持っている。
例えば うちは一族なら
火の性質を持つ一族で➡
For example, the Uchiha clan
has the property of fire,
and Fire Style Jutsu
is their strength.
火遁の術を得意としている。
風なら風遁。 雷なら雷遁。
例えば 千鳥は雷遁の術の一種だ。
Wind has the Wind Style.
And lightning has the Lightning Style.
Chidori is one type
of Lightning Style Jutsu.
てことは サスケは 火と雷の
２つの性質を持ってるってことか。
So that means Sasuke has
the two properties of fire
and lightning, huh...?
で お前は 現在ゼロ。
しかも どの性質変化が➡
And you currently don't have any.
Moreover, we don't know what type
of Chakra Property you're good at.
得意なタイプなのかも
まだ わからない。
なに？
What's that?
それを この紙切れで調べる。
I'll find that out with
this strip of paper.
どうやって？
How're you going to do that...?
雷の性質なら 紙にシワが入る。
The paper gets wrinkled
if it's a lightning property.
風なら切れる。
It'll get cut if it's wind.
火なら燃える。
It'll burn if it's fire.
水なら濡れる。
It'll get wet if it's water.
It'll crumble if it's earth.
土なら崩れる。
これは チャクラに
反応しやすい感応紙で➡
This is litmus paper that reacts
easily to Chakra.
チャクラを吸って育つ
特別な木から作られる。
It's made from a special tree
that grows while absorbing Chakra.
If you flow your Chakra
into this paper,
この紙に自分のチャクラを流し込めば
自分が どの性質かがわかる。
you'll find out
what property you have.
よ～し…。
All right...
フッ…！
フンッ！
お前のチャクラの性質は 風だ。
Your Chakra property is wind.
風…。
Wind...
It tears and cuts through
all sorts of things.
あらゆるものを
切り裂き 断ち切る。
It's Chakra with
outstanding battle strength.
戦闘力抜群のチャクラだ。
Ooh! I'm awesome!
おぉ～っ！ オレってば スゲエ！
No, you've still only just figured
out your property...
いや まだまだ
わかっただけだから…。
さて いよいよ 風の性質変化を
身につける修業だが…。
Now at last,
we've come to the training
for learning the Change
in Chakra Nature for wind...
オッス！
Right!
However, it will take an enormous
amount of time to learn that technique.
しかし そのテクニックを会得するには
膨大な時間がかかる。
で その時間を
大幅に短縮する方法を➡
And so I hit upon a way to
drastically reduce that time.
オレが思いついてしまった
というわけだな。
スゲエ！
で その方法は…。
Awesome!
And the way to do that is...
ヤマト隊長！
Captain Yamato!
Huh? Why, why?
あれ？ どうして？ どうして？
Kakashi asked me to help out
with this training.
(ヤマト)この修業は
ボクも協力するよう➡
カカシさんに頼まれたんだ。
I'm sorry for interrupting you,
Kakashi Senpai...
すみません カカシ先輩。
話の腰を折って。
No problem...
いやいや… でだな…。
あのさ… あのさぁ！
- And you see...
- Hey! Hey!
ヤマト隊長の木遁てば
どの性質変化になんの？
What type of Change in Chakra Nature
is your Wood Style, Captain Yamato?
(ヤマト)えっ？ それは…。
Huh?
Well...
まぁ アイツの興味が
そっちに移っちゃったから➡
Well, his interest has
shifted that way,
so just go ahead and tell him.
パッと教えてやってよ。
はぁ…。
Uh-huh...
じゃ…。
Then...
Earth Style: Rampart of Flowing Soil
土遁 土流城壁！
Whoa! What?!
うわっ！ なんだ…？
水遁 滝壺の術！
Water Style: Waterfall Basin Jutsu!
He made a waterfall...
滝ができた…。
I have two Chakra Properties,
earth and water.
ボクは 土と水の
２つの性質変化を持ってるんだよ。
What?! You have two of them,
Captain Yamato?!
えっ!? じゃ
ヤマト隊長も２つ 持ってるの？
Jonin-class Ninja generally
have two or more.
上忍クラスになると 皆 だいたい
２つ以上は持ってる。
I've also got properties other
than lightning that I can use.
オレも 雷以外にも扱えるしな。
そんじゃ ヤマト隊長は 木遁も含めて
３つ 持ってるのか？
Then, Captain Yamato has
three properties
including the Wood Style?
No, that isn't how it works.
いや そうじゃないんだな これが。
ん!?
Huh?
I can only use earth and water.
ボクは 土と水の２つしか使えない。
There is no fundamental property
known as "wood" to begin with.
そもそも 木なんていう
基本性質はないんだよ。
Then how do you do it?
じゃ どうやって？
同時にやるんだ。
He does it simultaneously.
He does the Change in Chakra Nature
for earth and water at the same time
土と水の ２つの性質変化を
同時に行い➡
and generates the new wood property.
木の性質を 新たに発生させる。
(ヤマト)右手に 土。 左手に 水。
Earth with my right hand...
and water with my left hand.
That's awesome...
すげぇ…。
If you have two Chakra Properties...
２つの性質変化を持ってる場合➡
it's not that difficult to use
each one independently.
それぞれを 独立して使うのは
たいして難しくない。
But when it comes to generating
(ヤマト)だけど ２つの性質変化を➡
two Change in Chakra Natures
at the same time...
同時に発生させるとなると
話は別。
it's a different story...
The power to generate a
new Chakra Property
２つの性質変化を同時に扱い➡
by using two Change in Chakra Natures
simultaneously
新たな性質変化を生み出す力を
血継限界っていうんだよ。
is called the Kekkei Genkai.
You've at least heard of
that expression, haven't you?
その言い方くらいは
聞いたこと あるだろ？
うん。
Yeah...
That boy you once fought
named Haku used it
かつて 戦った
白という少年もそうだ。
He was able to use the Kekkei Genkai
known as the Ice Style...
彼は 氷遁という
血継限界を使えたんだが➡
But he generated "ice" by using
風と水の ２つの性質変化を
同時に用いて 氷を発生させた。
the two Change in Chakra Natures
of wind and water at the same time.
It's a special Jutsu
あれは 血継限界を持つ一族だから
できる 特別な術だ。
only those from a clan possessing
the Kekkei Genkai can use.
あの白も…。
Haku, too, huh...?
So I couldn't copy it even with
my Sharingan...
(カカシ)だから オレの写輪眼でも
コピーできなかったんだ。
No kidding...
ふ～ん…。
Then what about Shikamaru's
Shadow Possession Jutsu
それじゃあさ シカマルの影真似とか
チョウジの倍化の術は どうなるの？
or Choji's Expansion Jutsu?
And what about Medical Ninjutsu
and Genjutsu?
それにさ 医療忍術とか幻術は
どうなっちまうの？
Hmm, an explanation of that stuff
would take a while
う～ん… その説明には
また 時間がかかるし➡
and you'll just get confused
if I tell you all at once...
一度に話すと混乱するからな。
Kakashi Senpai...
カカシ先輩！
Why don't you save the yin and yang of
Change in Chakra Nature for another time?
(ヤマト)陰と陽の性質変化については
また 今度にしたら どうです？
Yin? And Yang?
What's that?
陰？ 陽？ なんだってば？
Right.
そうだな。 今 言っても
どうせ お前にはわからん。
You wouldn't understand even
if I told you now.
Now, what were we talking about again?
さて どこまで話したっけな？
えっ!? あぁ… なんか
修業の時間をズルしまくる方法って。
Oh... Something about how
to totally cheat on training time...
Reduce the time.
短縮する だ。
Yeah, that.
So, how do we do that?
それ それ！ で… どうやって？
それはな…。
Well, you see...
(カカシ)それはな…。
うん うん！
Yeah? Yeah?
Multiple Shadow Clones.
多重影分身だ。
は…？
Huh?
いや だから
多重影分身なんだよ 実は。
As it happens, it's all about
Multiple Shadow Clones.
何が…？
What about them?
It's how we reduce the training period.
だから 修業期間を
短縮する方法だよ。
Hmm... I don't get it at all.
ん～ん… 全然
わかんないってばよ。
はぁ… じゃ これから
説明するけど ちゃんと聞けよ。
Okay, I'll explain now, so listen up.
Right. Please keep it
as simple as possible!
おっす！ なるべく
簡単に お願いするっす！
Okay, okay.
(カカシ)はいはい…。
Listen up...
いいか？
Regular Clones
You know that unlike regular clones,
影分身の術が
ただの分身と違って➡
実体そのものを作り出す
忍術だってのは知ってるな？
the Shadow Clone Jutsu is a Ninjutsu
for creating a real body itself, right?
Shadow Clones
Yeah, of course I do!
ああ もちろん知ってるってばよ！
ま 自分のコピー人間を
生み出す忍術だともいえる。
Well, you can also call it a Ninjutsu
for creating a copy of yourself.
I know because I can also use
the Shadow Clone Jutsu,
オレも お前ほどじゃないが➡
影分身の術を使えるから
わかるんだが➡
though not to your extent.
この術には 術者に及ぼす
ある特別な効果がある。
There is a particular effect this
Jutsu has on the caster.
お前も いつも使ってるから
え？
気づいているとは思うが…。
And since you're always using it,
I'm sure you've picked up on this...
影分身の分身体が
経験したことは➡
Anything experienced by
the Shadow Clone
is also experienced by the caster
術が解け 術者である
オリジナル１人に戻ったとき➡
その術者の経験として蓄積される。
after the clone has returned
to the caster's body.
I told you to keep it simple.
簡単にって言ったじゃん！
I knew you hadn't picked up on it.
やっぱ気づいてなかったのね。
I mean, I have no idea
what you're talking about.
…っつうかさ 言ってる意味
１つもわかんねえってばよ！
Then let's both try
creating Shadow Clones.
はぁ… なら２人で
とにかく影分身をやってみるぞ。
あ １体でいいからな。
へい！
Oh, one clone will be enough.
Right.
(２人)影分身の術！
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
よし じゃあ オリジナル側と
影分身側の二組にわかれて。
All right! Now let's split up into caster
and Shadow Clone teams...
The Shadow Clone team will
hide in the woods over there.
影分身の組は
向こうの林の中に隠れる。
影分身のナルトは ついてこい。
よっしゃ～！
Come with me,
Shadow Clone Naruto.
Right!
林の中の オレたち影分身組の姿は
オリジナルのほうからは見えない。
The originals can't see us,
the Shadow Clone team,
here in the woods.
And now only we,
will play rock-paper-scissors.
そこでだ オレたちのほうだけ
ジャンケンをするぞ。
What for?
なんで？
いいから ほら！
Just do it.
Hold it.
ああ 待って！
It won't be any fun if we just play
ordinary rock-paper-scissors.
ただ ジャンケンするだけじゃ
おもしろくないってばよ！
It's not supposed to be fun.
(カカシ)おもしろくなくても…。
Then the one who loses has
to treat the other to Ichiraku Ramen.
じゃあさ 負けたほうがさ
一楽ラーメン おごりね！
Okay, fine.
ああ わかったから！
やったぜ！
Yes! Now I'm fired up!
気合い入るってばよ！
(２人)ジャンケン…！
One, two...
影分身のほうは
何してんだってばよ？
What're the Shadow Clones doing?
You'll find out soon.
もうすぐわかる。
Yes!
やり～っ！ 勝った！
I won! You have to treat me,
Kakashi-sensei!
カカシ先生のおごりだってばよ！
はいはい。
Okay, okay. Now we're going to
break the Jutsu and vanish.
じゃあ オレたち影分身は
術を解いて消えるぞ。
Right.
おっす…！
ヘヘヘ…！
What were they doing?
ヤツらは何をしていた？
You have to treat me to Ichiraku Ramen,
Kakashi-sensei!
一楽ラーメン カカシ先生の
おごりだってばよ！
ジャンケンに勝ったからね！
I beat you at rock-paper-scissors!
勝手に約束しやがって…。
これで わかっただろ？
What're you doing arbitrarily
making promises like that?
Now you get it, right?
影分身の経験値は
オリジナルの中に蓄積されていく。
Shadow Clone experiences
are accumulated
within the original caster's body.
I get it...
なるほど… 今まで
なんとなく影分身してたから➡
I never realized it at all
because I was just sort of using
the Shadow Clones
without really thinking about it.
全然 気がつかなかったってばよ。
Normally, this Jutsu is used for
scouting dangerous locations
本来 この術は
危険な場所への偵察や➡
and gathering information by infiltrating
an enemy hideout, you see.
敵アジトに潜入して 情報収集に
使う術でもあるからな。
う～ん でも
それが わかったからって➡
But even having figured that out,
what does it have to do with
reducing the training period?
修業期間の短縮と
どう関係があるんだってばよ？
Okay, okay.
I'm going to explain that now...
はいはい これから説明するって。
ヘヘ… やり～っ！
Yes!
自来也様 螺旋丸なんて術を➡
Jiraiya-sama sure did a good job of
teaching the Rasengan Jutsu to this kid...
よく この子に
教え込めたもんだよ まったく。
I'll say.
Hurry! Hurry!
早く… 早く！
Basically, if you use a Shadow Clone
つまり 影分身を使って
同じ修業を ２人で行えば➡
and conduct the same training
with two people,
the experience will simply
be doubled, right?
経験値は 単純に➡
２倍ってことになるだろう？
うん うん。
Right. Right.
To put it a different way, it also means,
if you use two people,
言い換えると ２人でやれば➡
１人で 修業するときに
かかる時間を➡
it'll take half the time it takes
to train alone.
半分に短縮できるって
ことでもある。
And it'll take one-third
the time if you use three.
それが ３人なら ３分の１。
３人なら ３分の１… あ！
One-third with three.
1,000人なら 1,000分の１だ。
One-thousandth with a thousand.
そっか！
I see...
In other words, training that would
take two days alone
つまり
１人で ２日かかる修業は➡
will take one day with two people.
２人なら １日でできてしまうし➡
１人で 20年かかる修業でも
1,000人なら 約１週間でいい。
Even training that would take
twenty years alone
will take around a week with
a thousand people.
That's awesome!
So we can do it that way!
すっげぇ！
そんな手があったのか！
《ようやく わかってくれたのね》
He finally got it, huh...?
You'll conduct
the Change in Chakra Nature training,
(カカシ)これから 習得する
チャクラの性質変化の修業は➡
you're going to learn now,
常に 多重影分身を使って行う。
オッス！
using the Multiple Shadow Clones
at all times.
Right!
エッヘヘ カカシ先生が強い理由
わかったってばよ！
Now I know why you're so strong,
Kakashi-sensei!
So this is
how you did your training, huh?
このやり方で
いっつも修業してたんだな？
No, I've never even once
trained using this approach.
いいや オレは
一度も こんなやり方で➡
修業したことは ない。
え？ なんで？
Huh?! Why not?
You can also make
Shadow Clones, can't you?
だって カカシ先生も
影分身できるじゃん！
確かにな…。
Indeed I can...
But I don't have as much
Chakra as you do.
だが オレは お前ほど
チャクラを多く持っていないし➡
And I can't sustain
my Shadow Clones as long, either.
影分身の持続時間も 短い。
And the only types
of Jutsu suitable for me,
なんせ チャクラを
均等に分散してしまう術だけに➡
since I don't have much Chakra,
チャクラの少ない オレには
不向きな術だからな…。
are the ones requiring an
even distribution of Chakra.
そうなの？ オレってば➡
Really? I have more Chakra than you,
Kakashi-sensei?
カカシ先生より チャクラ量が多いの？
オレの 約４倍だ。
You've got around four times
more than me.
Huh?! I've got that much?!
I'm pretty awesome, aren't I?!
え!? そんなに!?
オレってば 結構すげぇんだな！
九尾のチャクラを 抑えなければ
約100倍だ。
If you didn't suppress the power
of the Nine-Tails Chakra,
you'd have around
a hundred times more.
九尾の チャクラ…。
The Nine-Tails Chakra...
That's why this is a training approach
only you can do.
(ヤマト)だから これは キミにしか
できない修業方法なんだよ。
あ…。
(ヤマト)だけど➡
But since it requires
a large amount of Chakra,
多くのチャクラを必要とするため➡
there's a possibility of rousing
the Nine-Tails Chakra.
九尾のチャクラを 呼び起こしてしまう
可能性がある。
And so I was summoned here in order
to control the Nine-Tails Chakra.
そこで ボクが呼ばれたんだ。
九尾のチャクラを
コントロールするためにね。
You're the one who hurt Sakura, Naruto.
((サクラを傷つけたのは…
キミだよ。 ナルト))
I'm ready!
頼むってばよ！
All right! First you must train
to strengthen your Chakra Property.
(カカシ)よし まずは
チャクラの性質変化が➡
より強くなるように 訓練する。
おう！
Right!
木の葉を 手のひらにはさんで
チャクラだけで切る。
Sandwich a leaf between your palms
and cut it just with Chakra.
Keep it there until you cut it right
in half, okay?
真っ二つになるまでな。
よ～し やるぞ！
All right! Let's do this!
(カカシ)さっきも言ったが
この修業は➡
And as I said before,
you'll do this training with Shadow Clones
at all times.
常に影分身で
やってもらう。
How many Clones should I make?
で… 何人くらいに
分身すればいいの？
Well, if you take
one person for one leaf...
う～ん…。
まっ １人 木の葉１枚として…。
あれぐらいかな。
(２人)ん？
Maybe around that many.
Huh?!
なっ …ヘヘヘ。
影分身の術！
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
ん！
《もう 切れ目が入ったか…。
Already got a little cut in, huh?
こりゃ案外 早いかもな…》
This might be quicker than I thought.
I look up at the rainbow I saw as a child.
kodomo no koro mita niji wo
But the prism colors are gone,
ima miageru to nanairo de wa naku
Shrouded in mist instead.
yagate kiri ga kakari
I search for you as you change,
jikan wa sugi kawatte yuku
With the passage of time but you're nowhere to be found.
kimi wo sagashite mo doko ni mo inai
I close my eyes and open my heart.
me wo toji kokoro hiraite
And stare hard again just to see if nothing really changes.
mata nagemete mite mo nani mo kawaranai no ka
I need to know.
tashikamete mitai
I make a wish that the mist will clear.
sunao ni narereba kono kiri ga hareru to
If I'm true to myself and shout it out.
kokoro ni negai sou sakenderu
Maybe by losing something.
nanika wo nakushite shimatta koto de sou
There must be something I gain as well.
te ni shita mono mo kitto arun darou
But we're still confused about adulthood.
dakedo mada bokura wa otona ni tomadoi
And searching for the means to live on.
ikito yuku sube sagashiteru
Next Episode
We've received a bad report.
It seems a village near the border
of the Land of Fire
was attacked by someone.
Was it the Akatsuki?
No. It seems the attacks were
by the Village Hidden in the Rain...
What did you say?
What're their intentions?
They might be intending to
take advantage
of the fact that the Akatsuki
are after Naruto-kun.
Either way, we must understand
the situation first.
Summon Asuma.
But...
What is it?
Naruto-kun is in the village.
Writhe
If there are less Jonin in the village,
his safety will come into question...
Next time: "Writhe"